Let's try a folkloric move that we call the Horsie Step.
This is base on some of the Arabian horses and the way that they toss their head up and down.
But there's varying degrees of how much you can exaggerate this movement.
Let's start with the more subtle version of it.
Let's start with our feet slightly together and our weighted leg is going to take most of the weight here.
And we're going to start with our foot, with the heel press toward the floor.
Our accent is going to be going down on the first beat.
So it's going to be on the downbeat.
So we're going to be going down and both knees are going to bend the same amount, okay.
So you don't want one leg here and this one more straight.
You want to keep them nice and even.
So as you bend, you're going to press into the floor.
So goes down, down, up, down, up, down, up.
Good.
Now you need to keep the body nice and relax here.
This is a folkloric move.
So you want it to be very natural looking.
Now we can also add a little bit of a chest lift there to contrast the movement down in your feet.
So as you heel presses, the chest is going to lift up, kind of like a garbage can lid.
So you're going to go, up and press and press and press.
So try this on both sides in the mirror and make sure your knees are staying nice and even.